gonutra.com 2011-06-19

# Privacy Policy - Market America

Important Messsage: Please Enable Cookies in your Web Browser to Continue. 

|  |  | privacypolicy  
---|---  
   
---  
| 

**_Your Market America Privacy Policy_**

We appreciate the trust you place in Market America, and we are committed to respecting your privacy and the security of your personal information. Our privacy policy describes the information we collect and how we use it.  
---  

**Information We Collect**

To best serve your needs, we will, from time to time, collect certain information from you. The information we collect may include, without limitation, your name, address, telephone number, email address, corporate information, testimonial, credit card information and date of birth. Personal information will be collected at various times including, without limitation, when you:

  * Register as a Preferred Customer
  * Order or reorder products, services and/or gift cards by telephone or on our website
  * Write an e-mail or letter to Market America
  * Sign up for Auto Ship
  * Submit a testimonial to Market America
  * Return an item or make an exchange
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event
  * Contact our customer service department
  * Navigate the website
  * Register on our website
  * Order products and services from our partner stores

**Using Information We Collect**

We want to provide you with the best possible internet experience and fulfill your orders exactly as you've requested. Additionally, we want to make your experience as a Market America Customer a pleasant one. In order to do this, we collect information that allows us to, without limitation:

  * Process your order
  * Match you up with the Customer Manager that is the best possible fit for you
  * Provide the products and services you request
  * Partner with stores where you like to shop
  * Send you promotional offers
  * Identify your product and service preferences
  * Customize our communications to you
  * Provide information concerning products you have purchased
  * Improve our product selection and customer service
  * Share your positive product testimonials with others
  * Include your name, stories, testimonials and images in Market America publications and literature or other media, on Market America operated websites, at Market America events, on Market America CDs and DVDs, in any other Market America communications to our Independent Distributors or others, or as otherwise deemed useful or appropriate by Market America.

**Information We Share with Others and Your Privacy Rights**

It is not a practice of Market America to sell, rent, or trade personal information. In order to service our customers and Preferred Customers, we will share your order information, some of your personal information and information about your spending habits with the Market America Independent Distributor assigned as your Customer Manager. Market America's Independent Distributors are obligated to treat the information you supply with confidentiality. 

We share certain limited information with the partner stores where you shop. Additionally, we contract with other companies to provide certain services, including without limitation credit card processing, IT consulting, printing, shipping, internet services, e-commerce, public and media relations. We make every effort to provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services. Generally, such companies are prohibited from sharing this information with anyone other than Market America or its Independent Distributors.

If you apply for the Market America credit card online and you live in the United States, you provide the financial information needed to process your application directly to Barclays Bank, the issuer and the administrator of the credit card program. Barclays Bank is a financial institution, independent of Market America. Barclays Bank has its own privacy and security policies, which you can review at [www.juniper.com](http://www.juniper.com/). Additionally, Barclays Bank is subject to the strict privacy regulations under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, 15 USC § 6801-6827.

If you apply for the Market America credit card online and you live in Canada, you provide the financial information needed to process your application directly to MBNA, the issuer and the administrator of the credit card program. MBNA is a financial institution, independent of Market America. MBNA has its own privacy and security policies, which you can review at [www.mbna.com/canada](http://www.mbna.com/canada). 

On rare occasions, we may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, or when required by law to do so. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.  

**Cookies**

Market America uses cookies on our websites. A cookie is a small data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer. Cookies allow us to enhance, personalize and track your online experience, so that the information you receive is more relevant to you. This technology will allow you to move faster through our website once the information is in our database since you do not have to re-enter the same information or log in each time you enter the site.  

**How We Use Email**

When you provide us your e-mail address, you may receive e-mails from us or from one of our Independent Distributors. E-mails may be sent in order to assist us in processing your order, respond to a request, provide customer service or inform you about products, services or promotional materials. It is our intent to send promotional e-mails only to those persons who wish to receive them. We provide instructions on how to unsubscribe in our e-mails.   

**Links to Other Sites**

We provide links on our Website to other sites. These sites operate independently of Market America and have established their own privacy and security policies. We encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit.  

**Updating or Reviewing Your Information**

You may review or update your customer or Preferred Customer information (name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card number, etc.) under Your Account.   

**Security**

Market America is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of information we collect, and we limit the information we provide to third parties. 

When you make a purchase or submit a document on our website, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format.  

**Privacy of Children on Our Web Site**

Our Web site is not intended for use by anyone under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under the age of 18.   

**Policy Changes**

From time to time, we may use customer information for unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change, we will post these changes in our website. We encourage you to review our privacy policy periodically.  

**Your Consent**

By using Market America facilities and continuing to order products and services, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as detailed in this privacy policy.  

**Contact Us**

We always welcome your questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us at [privacy@marketamerica.com](mailto:privacy@marketamerica.com).
